Jason Zhou

College Point, NY 11356 | 646-625-9905 | jzhou35@buffalo.edu <u>Github</u> | <u>Medium</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u>

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

Full-stack web developer experienced in JavaScript as well as Ruby on Rails with a background in Applied Mathematics and internship experience in a cloud native environment that included testing. **Programmer with strong skills** in team-building, project management, data structures and algorithms, debugging, and code optimization who positively contributes to an organization's objectives. **Engineer** with projects that incorporate front-end and back-end development with robust user interface (UI) and use optimal and efficient code to solve real-world problems.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript ES6 (*Proficient*), Ruby on Rails (*Proficient*), React (*Proficient*), HTML5 (*Proficient*), CSS (*Proficient*), SQL (*Familiar*), Java (*Familiar*), Python (*Familiar*)

Technologies: Git, Jupyter Notebook, Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint), Visual Studio, Eclipse, PostgreSQL, Heroku, Netlify, SQLite3, Redux, Docker, Kubernetes, Postman API

EXPERIENCE

Stark & Wayne LLC | Buffalo, NY | Cloud Engineering Intern

05/2019 - 08/2019

- Assisted in creating and maintaining a plugin to backup and restore ETCD with four different user authentication methods for SHIELD-an open source project.
- Developed BOSH manifest files to deploy automated tests to vSphere.
- Gained experience and familiarity with cloud native CI/CD pipeline methodologies using Concourse and Agile.
- Added support for ETCD in SHIELDPhalanx a bespoke BOSH release for testing the full-stack functionality.

Snowdays Shaved Cream Co. | Flushing, NY | Assistant Manager

08/2015 - 09/2016

- Reported financial and operational data to the manager daily, using MS Excel and showing a comprehensive and accurate overview of production that captured inventory, budget, and staffing numbers.
- Trained 10+ new team members to familiarize each with company's high standards; maintained strong retention rate among new hires.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Jobra - Github Frontend | Github Backend | Demo

(React, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, ChartJS)

A React application inspired by "Trello", that allows users to keep track of job applications with a data layer to allow the creation of ad hoc charts.

- Employed ActiveJob and ActionMailer to send a weekly reminder email to all users.
- Incorporated ChartJS to display real time changes with data and number of cards created per week for a month.
- Utilized multiple APIs to allow for a drag and drop feature.
- Enabled a search feature using ActiveRecord gueries to display filtered cards

Yourseum - Github Frontend | Github Backend | Demo

(React, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Netlify, Heroku)

A React application that takes favorite masterpieces out of the museum and places selections on a user's screen.

- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to implement real authentication.
- Validated backend using Ruby on Rails and Active Record to set rules and avoid redundancies.
- For best aesthetics and user interface, utilized React, Semantic UI React, and custom CSS to design frontend.
- Deployed application using Heroku for the backend and Netlify for the frontend.

Steam0.5 - Github Frontend | Github Backend | Demo

(JavaScript, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS)

A single-page application inspired by the existing games application, "Steam", that allows a user to connect and find common game interests with other users.

- Designed database schema with efficiency using REST API with Active Record, Ruby on Rails, and PostgreSQL.
- Encrypted for stronger security, utilizing BCrypt to salt and hash passwords.
- Created ability to see users' badges and games by traversing entity relational diagrams and extracting relevant data.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School | New York, NY | Full-Stack Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

11/2020 - 03/2021